Yogender Kumar

BACKEND ENGINEER

Profile

Experienced Back-end Engineer(Node.js, MongoDB, AWS) with over 7 years of experience in IT Industry. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction. Organized and dependable candidate successful at managing multiple priorities with a positive attitude. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals.

Employment History

Sr. Backend Developer(NodeJs, MongoDb, AWS), Noumena global

APRIL 2022 - DEC 2023

- Integrated Dwolla API to provide seamless bank and wallet payment solutions
- Utilized Plaid API to ensure secure bank account verification for user registrations
- Integrated Stripe for a robust card payment solution within the Noumena platform.
- Implemented Chargebee integration for streamlined subscription management
- Developed noumena.pro platform for entrepreneurs to register their businesses with Noumena
- · Working with the front-end team to integrate services.
- Writing complicated, reusable libraries for multiple services interaction and Real-Time Communication.
- · Client recognized as an effective team player
- Worked on AWS services like s3, SNS, SQS and sentry for Error Handling as well

Software Developer, SKUAD LAB INDIA Pvt. Ltd, Gurgaon

APRIL 2020 — MARCH 2022

- Developed Skuad Hire/Pay platform (skuad.io) to streamline the hiring process for Skuad and client companies
- · Managed candidate records, including resume details and interview tracking
- Implemented features for contract creation and payment between vendors and clients
- Enabled cookie-based authentication for secure user access
- · Built an identity service for user login and authentication across services
- · Utilized pandaDoc for seamless contract signing between two users
- Designed a platform for companies to hire candidates, sign contracts, and facilitate payments

Node Js Developer, App Street Software Pvt. Ltd, Gurgaon

JANUARY 2019 — MARCH 2020

- Designed and implemented the Linex system, revolutionizing customer loans and loan repayments for Cardekho
- Developed the Connex system, greatly improving the efficiency of car resale through auctions.
- Managed transactions and maintained ledger items for both Linex and Connex systems
- Defined and developed core logic for modules, establishing a solid foundation for the systems.
- Worked as a Backend Developer (Node.js) for Cardekho, specializing in selling/purchasing old cars through auctions.
- · Worked on Authentication and Authorization on server Side

Details

Chirawa, Jhunjhunu, Rajasthan

India

+917790915264

yogender3107@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Indian

Links

Linkedin

WWW

Skills

Node.js

MongoDB

GraphQL

Git

MySQL

JavaScript

React

Kanban

Kafka

Microservices

TypeScript

SQS

Hobbies

Bike Riding, Mountain Hiking, Running.

Associate IT, Daffodil Software Ltd, Hisar

JULY 2016 — DEC 2018

- Possess around 2 years of full software development life cycle experience in building large-scale enterprise systems using NodeJS, Object-Oriented Analysis and Design
- · Design Reusable Component In reactJs
- Contributed to the core product of Daffodil, collaborating with the Applane for Education Product team.
- Oversaw report cards and attendance management for students using the Applane for Education
- We are providing the some tool for helping to make Architecture
- Worked on lots of design tool for designing architect models
- · Worked on dynamoDb dataBase on this project
- · Used other services like SQS, SNS for Notification to Admin
- · Used APIDoc for creating a document for API.

Education

B.TECH, Rajasthan Technical University - Kota

MARCH 2012 — JULY 2016

Completed My B.Tech degree with Honours (70%)

Internships

Android Developer, Dotsquares, Jaipur

MAY 2015 — JULY 2015

Completed 60 days programming course in Android with Project 'Online Attendance System'.